# **ABOUT ME**

Hello! I am Abdullah Ameen and currently I am open for an opportunity to begin a career in the GIS, civil engineering or education field.

Recently I graduated with my master's degree in Cartography and Geographic Information System (GIS) from the University of Wisconsin-Madison.

In 2001, I graduated with my bachelor's degree in Civil engineering from Kabul University – Afghanistan.

I am a civil engineer by profession and have over 12 years of diverse experience in project management, water supply networks design, GIS analysis, education and social services.

Besides being a Civil Engineer, I am Cartographer, GIS Analyst, Graphic Designer, Mathematics Teacher, Static Web Developer and finally a Lifelong Learner.

During my junior and senior years at the university and as a fresh graduate from civil engineering faculty, I taught mathematics courses to high school students in Pakistan.

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

- English Advance Proficient
- Pashto Fluent
- Persian/Dari Fluent
- Hindi/Urdu Intermediate

#### **COMPUTER SKILLS**

- MS Office
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Python
- Web Development
- GIS and Web Mapping

#### **Graphic Design:**

- AutoCAD
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Graphic Manipulation

# **ABDULLAH AMEEN**

Madison, Wisconsin 53704 | Cell: (608) 609 2098 | Email: abdullah.ameenn@gmail.com

# QUALIFICATION

- Cartographer, civil engineer and educator with over 12 years of diverse experiences
- Skilled in spatial data analysis, visualization, presentations and web mapping
- Passionate about the art and science of writing code and making maps
- Project manager with proven experience in planning, budgeting and implementation
- Adept at coordination, communication and negotiation with project stakeholders
- Detail-oriented, patient, problem solver and well-organized

### **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN - MADISON - JAN 2017 - MAY 2020

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN CARTOGRAPHY AND GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SYSTEM (GIS)

UNIVERSITY OF KABUL - AFGHANISTAN - MAR 1997 - DEC 2001

**BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN CIVIL ENGINEERING** 

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **GIS Intern**

Telephone and Data Systems (TDS) | Oct 2019 - Present

- Add easements and the Right of Way permits to databases
- Upload/draw subdivision plats and certify survey maps into geodatabases
- Created a web map to visualize and track the Right of Way (ROW) workflow
- Searched and downloaded over 6000 subdivision plats and certify survey documents
- Draw public utility easement lines on subdivision plats in ArcGIS and in ArcGIS online

#### Math/Science Instructor

Forward Service Corporation | May 2018 - Aug 2019

- Developed Upward Bound academic year curriculum for high school students
- Guided students on 5-week summer program to one of Wisconsin's universities
- Conducted ACT prep training in math and science sections
- Tutored 60 students in math/science on regular basis

### **Case Manager**

Porchlight Inc. | Aug 2016 - Mar 2018

- Helped clients obtain stable housing and employment
- Referred clients to available community resources
- Provided daily advocacy and case management to 10 permanent and 15 walk-in clients
- Assisted clients in maintaining stable housing and employment

## Substitute Teacher/AVID Tutor

Madison School District | Sep 2015 - Feb 2018

- Provided classroom support to teachers and students
- Facilitated tutorial sessions for students in math and science
- Taught and managed a class of 25-30 students

### **Program Support Unit Manager**

AECOM International Development - SIKA-East - USAID | Feb 2012 - Sep 2014 - Afghanistan

- Planned, budgeted, and coordinated field activities for 21 districts and 6 provinces
- Served as a liaison among program/project stakeholders and SIKA-East senior management
- Launched/introduced SIKA-East program to relevant institutions and to the public at the sub national level
- Provided technical support to program and operations staff

## **Regional Manager**

The Asia Foundation – Performance Based Governors' Fund PBGF Program - USAID | Jan 2010 – Feb 2012 - Afghanistan

- Planned, budgeted, coordinated, and evaluated the PBGF program for 4 provinces.
- Analyzed and presented performance evaluations of provincial governors' offices in ArcGIS
- Assisted provincial governors' offices with quarterly and annual budgeting
- Monitored budget categories to ensure expenditures were in line with program guidelines

# **Engineering Manager (Environmental Health)**

International Rescue Committee (IRC) - National Solidarity Program | Mar 2005- June 2009 - Afghanistan

- Supervised 25 district engineers
- Trained district engineers in CAD, GIS, use of Garmin GPS and design of water supply networks
- Checked technical accuracy of sub-project proposals prior to donor submission
- Contributed to establishment of more than 200 Community Development Councils (CDCs)
- Surveyed and designed over 30 community-based water supply network projects

# **Design Engineer (Water Supply and Sanitation)**

Danish Committee for Afghan Refugees (DACAAR) | June 2002 - Mar 2005 - Pakistan and Afghanistan

- Surveyed and designed water supply network projects using GPS, GIS and MS Excel
- Provided technical support to field teams during project implementation
- Inspected quality of drinking water before the survey and inauguration of a project
- Served as a lead team of a water supply and sanitation program for 10 Afghan refugees camps in Northwestern Pakistan